Adam Song

Senior Software Engineer

as.asuperstar05@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/adam-song005/ • Wroclaw, Poland

Summary

Adam is a senior software engineer with a demonstrated history of working in various industries, including eCommerce, finance, telecommunications, healthcare, and many others. His experience with full-lifecycle work across multiple fields makes him a valuable asset to any team. He also gained valuable experience working with startups, launching new projects from scratch. He has a deep understanding of both front-end and back-end technologies. He is a fast learner with a passion for technology and innovation.

Experience

SoluLab

Senior Software Engineer

03/2022 - 07/2024

- Developed and maintained high-quality software products by adding new features or fixing bugs, and wrote unit and e2e tests to ensure code quality and system functionality.
- Made crucial decisions regarding tech stack and system design that had a significant impact on the success
 of the product.
- Designed and developed high-performing backend systems using modern technologies and frameworks, such as Node.js, PHP/Laravel, Java/Spring Boot, and Python/Django.
- Created scalable and efficient frontend systems using JavaScript (React, Next.js, and Vue.js) and ensured seamless integration with the backend.
- Utilized serverless architecture to achieve scalability and AWS Cloud technologies, including Lambda, API Gateway, Cognito, SSM, EC2, CloudFormation, S3, SNS, RDS, and EventBridge.
- Participated in developing Android 12 OS and customized core system apps (Launcher, Settings, System UI) and other apps using Java and Kotlin.
- Proactively identified and addressed technical challenges and issues, including performance optimization and security vulnerabilities, to maintain product quality and ensure customer satisfaction.

Ceneo

Full Stack Engineer

06/2021 - 02/2022

- Worked on both the backend and frontend of the platform, using PHP(Laravel) and Typescript(React, Node.js).
- Developed responsive desktop and mobile version of applications using React, Next,js, and integrated with GraphQL APIs.
- Developed 15+ Android mobile applications for various clients, such as a job search engine, household utility provider, online review service, and car manufacturer.
- · Conducted system performance analysis and optimization to enhance scalability, reliability, and security.
- Integrated third party APIs for the payment gateway setup like PayPal and Stripe, and established email and text messaging services using Sendgrid, Twilio and AWS SES.
- Maintained a high level of quality assurance through the development and implementation of unit testing and integration testing.

Full Stack Engineer 03/2019 – 05/2021

• Revamped the outdated legacy PHP application to a Laravel, Vue.js based application, increasing the application's performance by 50%.

- Solved complex performance problems and architectural challenges.
- · Coached the team members with paired programming and code reviews.
- · Worked with senior technical staff to choose architecture and most appropriate technologies for the project.
- · Undertook code reviews, and provided evaluation and feedback on the production of work.
- · Attended project retrospectives and contributed as appropriate.
- Worked with the business owner and customers to maintain scale and develop new features and functions across platforms.
- Stayed up-to-date with emerging trends and technologies, making recommendations for system improvements and process optimization.

Wezom

Front End Developer

07/2017 - 03/2019

- Optimized performance and functionality of PHP-based frameworks (Drupal, Laravel, Symfony, and WordPress) by modifying full-stack elements and improved site loading speed and user experience.
- Worked with a team to build a comprehensive e-commerce platform for both buying and selling housing blueprints.
- Maintained communication and relationships with stakeholders and clients to ensure estimates and projects were delivered on time.
- Converted Sketch, Figma, InVision design into pixel perfect HTML layouts.
- Fixed issues connected with HTML/CSS/JS on a project based on CMS WordPress.
- Developed new theme for CMS WordPress in collaboration with PHP dev.
- Developed new features/components using React UI library called Ant Design in collaboration with React JS devs.

Education

University of Edinburgh

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

2013 - 2017

Skills

React, Next.js, Nest.js, Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, Spring Boot, Django, Flask, Laravel, Symfony, Drupal, WordPress, Web3.js, Webflow, AWS, GCP, Android, Docker, Kubernetes, GraphQL, CMS, Rest APIs, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, CI/CD, Jest, Cypress, PHPUnit, Enzyme, Git, Github Actions, Jira, Agile, OOP, MVC, Java, Kotlin, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Figma, Sketch, Responsive Design, TailwindCSS, Material UI